

(647) 231 1648

timlemke.github.io

London ON Canada



Front End web developer living and working remotely from London ON. Kind, inclusive team player, creative thinker and problem solver. Over four years of professional experience in both B2B SaaS and agency settings. Loves coffee, superheroes and LEGO.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Intermediate Front End Developer

tbk Creative | 2021 - Present

Currently working with the talented and agile team at tbk Creative to create custom websites and web applications for some of Canada's most prolific brands.

- Working daily with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Storybook, jQuery, Bootstrap, SCSS (Sass), Less, Parcel, Webpack, Gulp, Grunt, Webpack, WordPress and PHP among other languages, tools and technologies.
- Delivering code changes and completing work in a fast paced, agile environment.
- Involved in mentoring and training junior developers.

Developer

SeventyEight Digital Inc. | 2018 - 2021

- Developed web sites and applications for numerous clients across many different industries.
- Worked daily with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Foundation for Sites, SCSS (Sass), Gulp, Webpack, Kentico CMS (Portal Engine and MVC Solutions), WordPress, C#, ASP.NET, Web Forms and MVC, Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator, Git, GitHub, Bitbucket and Sourcetree, among other languages, tools and technologies.
- Was actively involved in all stages of development life cycle, including interfacing with clients

Junior Web Developer

Advanced Utility Systems Inc. | 2017 - 2018

- Worked daily with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, DotNetNuke, C#, ASP.NET, SVN and Jira. Also worked daily with web accessibility testing tools including JAWS, NVDA, ChromeVox, Compliance Sheriff and Siteimprove among other languages, tools and technologies.
- Worked alongside QA department to improve accessibility of current web application and to ensure it meets current WCAG and AODA standards. Actively involved in accessibility testing, identifying and addressing issues.
- Organized internal web accessibility training sessions for developers to create and maintain internal accessibility development standards.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Front End Development

Master of Music

Juno College of Technology (2017)

University of Toronto (2014 - 2016)

SKILLS

Technical

JavaScript/React/Angular/Vue
Typescript/Storybook/jQuery

PHP/C#

Node.js/ASP.NET

WordPress/Shopify/Kentico

HTML5/CSS3

WCAG/AODA

SCSS/Less

Bootstrap/Foundation

Webpack/Gulp/Grunt

NPM/Git

GitHub/GitLab/Bitbucket

Photoshop/Illustrator

...and always learning more...

Professional

Self-managed

Excellent Communicator

Problem Solver

Strong Collaborator

Good Time Management

INTERESTS

Coffee

Guitar

LEGO

Hiking